Right now, I'm going to show you the
easiest possible way to supercharge your
AI agents, and it's all thanks to MCP
servers. You might have heard of them
before, but there is a new way to set
them up and connect them to your agents
super quickly. The workflow that you're
looking at right here, and I'll actually
show you this later in the video, took
me only 10 minutes to set up. I
connected my Claw desktop to YouTube,
Obsidian, Slack, and GitHub really,
really easily. And so I have this whole
workflow here where it pulls a YouTube
transcript. It summarizes that and puts
it in my Obsidian vault and then I have
it read my Slack conversation to get
some extra context and then create a
GitHub issue and then I even have it
mention Claude code in the issue to kick
off a cloud code agent to autonomously
work on my codebase based on the
research that I did here. So end to end,
we started with research all the way to
a complete implementation in our
codebase and it took me 10 minutes to
set this up with all of these MCP
servers. Now you might be asking
yourself, Cole, isn't that going to take
a while to get everything set up? I
mean, if you worked with MCP before, you
probably worked with this kind of
registry, like the main one that we have
in GitHub where you find the MCP servers
that you want in this list, but then you
have to click into it and you have to
figure out the JSON configuration to
connect it and then you have to go and
do that for the next one and the next
one. It actually is a bit of a hassle to
get all of these MCP servers, all this
functionality built into our AI agents.
But now there is a new tool that makes
it 100 times easier to find and connect
MCP servers and that is the Docker MCP
catalog. This is what I want to show you
today and all the things that we can do
with it. It is a beautifully curated
list of all of these MCP servers and
with a single click of a button I can
connect them and then use them in my own
agents. I can connect very easily again
with a click of a button to cloud code
or cloud desktop. This is now my command
center to manage my MCP servers. Right
now, I'll show you how easy it is to get
this up and running and then we'll play
around with some of these different
servers and build out some workflows.
So, in order to get access to this
lovely catalog of MCP servers, the only
thing you have to do is install Docker
Desktop. And if you followed along with
any of my content in the past, you
probably already have it. I use Docker
already for pretty much every
application that I build. And so I
already have the platform up and running
24/7 with all of my different
containers. And so now I get to manage
my MCP servers in the exact same place.
It is a beautiful thing. So cool. Let's
actually explore all the MCP servers
that we have here. And I'll show you how
easy it is with a single click of a
button to connect these servers into any
of your external clients as well. Once
you have your server selected like cloud
code, cloud desktop, Gemini CLI, it'll
actually update the configuration for
these tools for you. So you don't even
have to do anything with JSON yourself
like you have before if you've used MCP.
And so yeah, going back to the catalog,
I have this sorted by popularity right
now. We've got fetch at the top with
over 500,000 downloads already, giving
our agents the ability to take a URL and
extract the content from it. We've got
Slack. I'm going to be using this one
today. Playright for front-end testing.
Context 7 for rag. We can hook our
agents into our database in one click.
We can pull YouTube transcripts. I'll
also be using that one today. It feels
like whatever functionality I need for
my agent, I can get it from this
catalog. We got notion. We've got Brave,
Firecrawl for scraping. We've got
Discord, Stripe, Chroma DB. It's like
everything is here. It's so cool. So,
let's actually install one of these. I'm
going to go to YouTube transcripts.
click into this and then all I have to
do, one click, add MCP server. Boom, we
have it now connected. The only other
thing you might need to do depending on
your MCP is set up configuration. But
it's also really convenient that we can
do all of this for things like API keys
right within the catalog as well. And
then we can also see all of the tools
that this MCP now gives to our agent
once we have it connected. Also keep in
mind that when you are working with the
MCP toolkit, which is in beta, you might
need to go to your Docker settings in
the top here, and go to beta features
and enable it. Now, this was enabled for
me by default, but I just want to call
that out in case you're missing that
there, cuz then it's not going to work
when we go on to the rest of the things
here, actually getting these MCP servers
connected to our agents. So now with our
first server selected from the catalog,
we can now hook this in to any of our
clients in the click of a button. But
there's one other thing I actually want
to show you first that's really cool.
Because when you go to this client page
for the first time, none of these will
be connected except for this one right
here, Ask Gordon. It's actually set up
to be connected to our MCP toolkit by
default because Gordon is the AI agent
that is built directly into Docker
Desktop, also in beta, just like the MCP
toolkit. And so without even having to
connect to any external client yet, we
can actually test our MCP servers
directly within Docker Desktop thanks to
Gordon. And so for the tool that I have
right now, you just have to go to your
toolbox MCP toolkit right here. And then
just make sure that you have the toolkit
enabled for Gordon. And so I have my
three tools right now for that YouTube
transcript MCP server. So I'll close out
of this. And we need it to transcribe a
video. So I'm just going to go to one of
the latest videos on my channel where I
cover Dockling, which is a tool to help
with data extraction and chunking for
rag. And so I'm just going to copy this
URL at the top. Very simple. Go back to
Gordon here. I'm going to say transcribe
this video and give me a very concise
summary. I just want something really
fast here just to show you how Gordon is
a place for us to quickly test our MCP
servers. And so Gordon is going to make
that tool call. There we go. Calling get
transcript. And it's a pretty quick
agent overall. So we should get the
summary in just a second here. There we
go. Nice. The video introduces Dockling.
Didn't quite spell it right. I'll give
it a pass on that one. Free open source
Python tool designed simplify the
extraction and preparation of complex
data. Cool. This is perfect. So, as
we're adding these servers in our
catalog, we can use Gordon to quickly
test them. But the real deal here is
being able to use these MCP servers in
our existing clients. You maybe are
using Claude code or cursor for your
coding or you're just working with cloud
desktop to brainstorm with an LLM. Let's
give the functionality to those guys.
And so, all we have to do is go to the
clients tab and then single click of a
button. Just as easy as selecting the
servers in our catalog. So, we'll start
with Claw Desktop here. All I have to do
is click connect. And boom, there we go.
Now, the next time we open up Cloud
Desktop, all of the servers that we have
here are going to be immediately
available in Cloud Desktop. Now, for
most MCP clients, once we add more
servers into them, we have to restart
them. So, I'll do that for Cloud Desktop
here. I'll just go and rightclick, quit,
and then go and restart the application.
Super super fast. Wait for it to load.
And then the way that we can verify our
connection here is by going to search
and tools and then you're looking for
the MCP server called mcp_doccker
very creatively named. And we can click
into this to see all the tools that it
exposes. And so this single server is
basically aggregating all the tools from
all the MCPs that we have selected in
the catalog. So once we start adding
more here, we're going to just see it
still as a single server in our client
just with all the tools from all of our
different servers. And the other thing I
want to say here, I think you'll find
this interesting. This is a quick 30-
secondond explanation how this works.
All of these tools that we add, they run
as Docker containers. So whenever our
client like Claw Desktop requests to use
a tool like to get a transcript, that
actually quickly spins up a container to
perform that tool action and then once
the tool is done running, it immediately
spins the container down. So no matter
how many MCP servers we have connected
here, it's not like those containers are
constantly running taking memory on our
machine. It's only when we're using a
tool that the container is actually
running. So extremely efficient and
secure. Very, very cool. And so now with
Claw Desktop here, I'm just going to go
ahead and test it with the exact same
thing. So I'll copy this URL, go back in
and say transcribe this video, and give
me a super concise summary. All right.
So, we'll just make sure that it can
work as well as Gordon, which quick
spoiler, Cloud Desktop does work quite a
bit better than Gordon. It is a lot more
powerful of an LLM running things under
the hood. So, there we go. It's calling
MCP Docker to get the transcript for the
URL. And let's see if we can get a nice
summary here. Awesome. Perfect. Yep.
Here's our video, what it covers, key
features. Looking really good. Honestly,
probably even a better summary. So,
cool. That is the YouTube transcript
MCP, but let's add in a few more, really
spice things up, and actually get a full
workflow created with these MCP servers.
So, I'm just going to connect a few
different ones that I want to have in my
Claw desktop. So, I'm going to start
with Slack here. I'll go ahead and add
this server. Single click. Boom. There
we go. And then we just have to
configure a couple of things, which I
already did off camera for the team ID
and the channel IDs. You just get these
from the Slack URLs. And then you just
have to create a Slack app and hook in
the bot token here. I'm not going to
cover that right now. Uh you can read
the documentation in Slack if you want.
So I got Slack connected. What else do
we want here? How about uh GitHub? So I
did actually try the official GitHub and
that one wasn't working for me for some
reason. So I'm just going to use the
archived one here because this has
actually been working phenomenally for
me. So now all I have to do is add in my
personal access token that I can get in
my GitHub settings. And now it can
access all my repositories and do things
like create issues on my behalf. Very,
very neat. And then the last one that I
want to add in here, I've been
absolutely loving Obsidian recently.
Probably going to be creating a lot more
content on it in the near future. So,
I'm going to go ahead and add this one.
Obsidian is where I do a lot of my note
takingaking and knowledge management.
Like what you're looking at right here
is actually the script that I have
written out for this video right now. I
know it's really meta u but yeah, when
you go into the settings for Obsidian,
you can install community plugins. And
one of these plugins that you can
install is called the local rest API. So
you have to install this and then it's
going to give you an API key, which is
what you need to hook into the Obsidian
API key right here in the MCP
configuration. So that's how you hook in
Obsidian. Now going back to my servers,
I have four in total now. So I have 26
tools for GitHub, which is kind of a
lot, but we'll roll with it here. Then
we've got Obsidian, Slack, and YouTube
Transcripts. And so we can start to
actually define these workflows for the
large language model to combine
functionality from these different
servers. It's really cool. Now, I'm not
going to be testing this with Gordon.
Gordon is a pretty cool guy, but I can
tell from my testing that I've been
doing that it's not powered by the most
powerful LLM. It seems like it's
something like Gemini 2.5 Flash or GPT5
Nano. it gets quite overwhelmed with all
of these tools when it has more than a
couple. And plus, I think Gordon is more
fine-tuned to help you with Docker
related things anyway. And so with all
these tools connected, I'm just going to
jump straight to restarting Cloud
Desktop and testing things in Cloud
Desktop. And I could connect other
clients as well, like if I wanted to
connect it to Cloud Code or Gemini CLI,
but I'll keep on the the train here of
Claude Desktop because I love using
Cloud Desktop just to generally
brainstorm ideas with an LLM. So yeah,
let's go do search and tools. Scroll
down MCP Docker. I'll click into this
and sure enough, this time we have a
much larger list of tools because we
have everything from Slack, Obsidian,
YouTube Transcripts, and GitHub.
Awesome. So, I can say, for example,
what Slack channels do I have? And it
should just say I have access to a
research channel because that's the only
one that I've given the Slackbot access
to. So, yep, listing Slack channels. In
a second here, it should say research.
There we go. Okay, perfect. Yep. So, the
Slack MCP is working for GitHub. I can
say what GitHub repos do I have? And in
a second here, I'll actually combine
some of these tool usages together to
make something pretty interesting. But
yeah, first let's just make sure that
these servers are actually working.
There we go. I have 50 GitHub repos.
Take a look at that. That's actually
crazy to me. Yeah, things are working
great. Okay, so that was fun just
testing out the different MCP servers,
seeing these tools in action. But now,
let's take it to the next level. This is
where the fun really begins because I
wanted to create more of a workflow for
my agent to go through leveraging the
different MCP servers in tandem to
accomplish a single larger task for me.
Let's push the limits of Sonnet 4.5
here. And so what I'm going to do is
send in this request that is going to
require it to work with all four MCP
servers that it has through the Docker
catalog. So I'm having it pull the
transcript for that same Dockling video.
I want to create a summary and put it in
my Obsidian Vault. And I'm specifically
having it put it in this reference notes
folder right here. And I'll actually
delete the previous dockling summary
that I have just so that it's starting
from scratch. There we go. put it in the
reference notes folder. Then after I
want it to read my Dockling research
that I have in that single Slack channel
that it has access to. So just giving it
some more context to then create a
GitHub issue for Archon. I want to
actually integrate Dockling with Archon.
And then finally last thing we're asking
a lot here. Finally, I wanted to add a
comment to the issue saying at cloudfix
work on this issue. That is our way to
trigger cla code to autonomously work on
this issue. So, we're going from the
research phase all the way to actually
kicking off a workflow for Cloud Code to
work on this issue in our repository. I
know this is pretty complex, but that is
the point. I'm trying to ask a lot here
and see how it performs. And I'm
actually super curious. I have not run
this yet. This is my first time doing
it. And so, we'll see if it's able to
accomplish everything. And so, yeah,
first it is getting the transcript. I
think what I'm going to do here is let
it run. I'll pause and come back once
it's done. We'll read through the
conversation history together and see if
it did what it was supposed to. Okay,
this is actually beyond exciting.
Everything worked flawlessly. And as I'm
speaking, Claude Code is working on this
issue. Take a look at this. This is just
so cool. So, it got the transcript. We
saw that already before I I paused to
come back here. Then, it is creating the
research summary in Obsidian. Take a
look at this in the reference notes
folder. I've got Dockling YouTube
tutorial summary. And it even spelled
Dockling right this time. good for
Sonnet 4.5. So, we got our nice little
summary here of the tool as a whole.
Looks really good. Talks about hybrid
chunking, which is one of the things
that I care about. And then going down
now, it goes and it fetches the
conversation history in that Slack
channel. So, it lists the channels,
finds that research one, it pulls the
channel history. So, there's quite a bit
of text that I have here, just things
that I did to research Dockling. Looking
really good. Then, it searches my GitHub
repositories to find the Archon one.
Once it finds archon, then it creates
the issue. And it had a problem creating
an issue the first time it used that
tool call. But LLMs are quite smart,
especially sonnet 4.5. So it's able to
correct itself, figure out the problem,
call the tool again, and this time it
works creating that issue for the
dockling integration. And then finally,
it adds that comment to trigger cla
work on this issue. And so yeah, let's
actually go to our browser. Now, I want
to show you here first. This is the
research that I have in the Slack
conversation that it pulled by the way.
Then going into archon, we have a new
issue. Look at that. Integrate dockling
for advanced document processing in the
rag pipeline. We got a beautifully
formatted issue here. And there we go.
Atcloudfix work on this issue. And then
cloud code that I already have
integrated in the repository responded
to this and is in the middle of
processing creating a pull request for
my issue. So end to end from cloud
desktop. I had to do a ton of research
that now finalizes. It culminates into
Cloud Code actually working on this for
me. Super super cool. All right, Claude
Code has finished its work. It did it
all within a feature branch that I
created a poll request for as well. So,
we can go to that, check it out, and
boom, there we go. We have a poll
request that was created end to end by
automation thanks to MCP servers and the
Docker catalog. Now, I didn't check its
work yet here, but that's not the point.
It's totally good if you don't
understand Archon or exactly what I'm
doing at GitHub here. The point that I'm
trying to drive home is just how easy it
was to create this agentic workflow with
all these MCP servers that we connected
in just a couple of clicks. Now, what we
were able to do here in Cloud Desktop
was pretty incredible. And it's really
easy for us to connect to other clients
that are in this list as well,
especially if you want to take some of
these MCP servers and use them with your
coding assistants. Most of the clients
here actually are coding assistants that
you can connect to. But the big question
I have is how can we use these MCP
servers in our own custom agents within
Python code within NADN. Well, that's
what I'm going to show you right now. To
end things off for this video, I want to
show you how we can take all this
functionality and use it anywhere. So,
we're not just limited to this client
list. As awesome as this list is, and it
does cover the tools that I use
generally, what about my own agents? So,
we'll actually start by going back to
Cloud Desktop because I want to show you
that the way that Docker connects to
these clients is the same way we can
connect to our custom ones. There's just
a little bit of extra setup we have to
do. So, let's go to the settings here.
Let's see how exactly this connection is
set up between the Docker catalog and
cloud desktop. If we go to the MCP
Docker server here, take a look at this.
It is using this thing called the Docker
MCP gateway. What the heck is the MCP
gateway? Well, it is the tooling under
the hood that allows us to connect the
MCP servers in the Docker catalog to all
of those clients in that preconfigured
list. But the beautiful thing with this
MCP gateway is it is actually
opensourced. And so we have this
documentation page that I'll link to in
the description where they talk about
this. The MCP gateway is Docker's
open-source enterprise ready solution
for orchestrating and managing MCP
servers. So the exact same functionality
that is used under the hood to connect
with our catalog and that preconfigured
set of clients like cloud desktop and
cloud code, we can use that same
functionality. We can run it ourself and
then connect our own agents like what I
have right here in N8N. And I'll show
you this in a second here. And so going
to their open source repo for MCP
gateway, they have some instructions for
setup. You basically build the gateway
from source and then we can run it with
a couple of different commands depending
on the MCP protocol specifically that we
want to use. Now HTTP streamable is the
de facto standard protocol for MCP. So
this is the command that I'm going to
run myself. So, I followed the
instructions in this readme to get
everything up and running locally
already. So, now I can run docker MCP
gateway and I'm going to run it on port
8089 and I'm going to use the streaming
transport layer for MCP. So, I'll run
this and it's going to look at my Docker
catalog registry and it's going to
figure out the MCP servers that I have
connected. So, the exact same ones that
we connected within Docker Desktop in
the UI with the catalog we have
available here. And so it's going to run
all of these. And so now we have the
server listening on port 8089. It's
ready to receive any requests for any of
the tools for any of these servers. It
is that easy to get this all up and
running. And so now in N8, I'll just
show you really quickly. And now we can
do this with like any agent that we
want. N is just like the easiest way to
take advantage of this right out the
gate. So I have a chat trigger that goes
to a super basic AI agent. Like this is
like extremely barebones right now. I'm
just using GPT4.1 mini for my LLM. And
then for the MCP client, the connection
here is host.doccker.in
because I have to look outside of the n
container to my host machine where I'm
running the docker mcp gateway. And then
the port obviously is 8089 because
that's exactly what I selected when I
ran the gateway. And then the server
transport is HTTP streamable. And then
everything's running locally. So, I
don't have any authentication at this
point. Super easy to get it set up. So,
I'll go back to the canvas here. I can
actually open the chat and show you
here. Let's do something like, you know,
what Slack channels do I have? I'm not
going to do like a whole complex
workflow again because we already saw
that in action, but we can just quickly
see it leverage the MCP client. It used
the Slack list channels here. And we
have our research channel. Cool. And
then I can actually go to the MCP
gateway logs and I can see the logs from
the N8N. So, first we have the
connection that's made here from N8N and
then it's running this specific tool to
list the channels that we have, Slack
list channels, and it took 1.5 seconds
in total. So, absolutely beautiful. And
I also did a video recently on my
channel showing you how to build live
kit voice agents. And there I did show
very briefly using the Docker MCP
gateway to connect to the servers I have
in the catalog. And so definitely check
out the video I'll link to right here if
you want a full guide on building
LiveKit voice agents. But right here, I
just want to show you another example of
using our custom agents to talk to these
MCP servers that we've curated. And so
in my agent session, I've just added
this MCP servers parameter where I'm
connected to the same URL that we used
in N8N. So again, connected to the same
servers that we were using in Claw
Desktop and N8N. So in my console here,
I can go ahead and run this voice agent
and let's see it in action.
>> Hello, how can I assist you today?
>> Yeah, my GitHub username is Cam0000.
I want you to search my repos and find
the one that has the most stars and tell
me what it is.
>> The repository with the most stars under
your GitHub username, Colium0000
based on the top results is Archon. It
is described as the beta release.
>> That is the right answer. So I'll go
ahead and close out of that there. But
there you go. We have a live voice agent
that is connected to all the servers
that we have curated in our Docker
catalog. So there you go. That my friend
is everything that I have to cover right
now for the Docker MCP catalog. And huge
thanks to Docker for actually
collaborating with me on this video just
to make sure that I was hitting on all
of the important features that we have
with the MCP catalog. It really is the
easiest way to bring external
functionality into our AI agents like I
showed you in this video. So, if you
appreciated this video and you're
looking forward to more things AI and AI
agents, I'd really appreciate a like and
a subscribe.